Garo Arslanian 1557 Amberlea Rd. Pickering, Ontario, L1V4V4 416 902 1057 arslanian1@gmail.com

Dear Hiring Manager,

I am an Engineer In Training (EIT), a graduate of the Civil Engineering Bachelor degree from Lakehead University; I also obtain a Civil Engineering Technology diploma from Seneca College. I have filled on-site Construction Project Coordinator/Engineer positions for general contractors at various ICI private and public sector projects for City of Toronto and TTC, as well as, Contract Administrator and inspection at engineering firms.

My previous work experiences combined with my education, I have gained the necessary background knowledge that will allow me to excel within your organization. As a Project Coordinator/Engineer for a GC, and work along the PM to review Structural/Architectural drawings and solve on-site issues; in addition, process and administrate Submittals, Change Orders, RFIs, and addendums to the contract. I prefer a position in the GTA region. I stronglyfeel that my skills and knowledge learned within the construction industry can better further your organization's accomplishments, as well as, extend my knowledge to new aspects of engineering.

I look forward to discuss how my skills can help achieve your goals, moreover, to putmy knowledge and experience into practice. Thank you in advance for your consideration.

Yours truly, Garo Arslanian

GARO ARSLANIAN

Home phone: 905 492 5000, Cell 416 902 1057, arslanian1@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE:

Seeking a position in the Civil Engineering field where I can contribute my analytical and handson knowledge along with on-site construction experience.

SKILLS SUMMARY:

- Engineer In Training (EIT) by Professional Engineers Ontario.
- Superior computer skills in AutoCAD, Structural design SAFE, E-Tabs, and Scheduling program Microsoft Project (similar to Primavera).
- Able to multi-task and handle stress in a fast-paced environment, demonstrated from several jobs.
- Organized, efficient and hard-working.
- Fully licensed driver with access to a vehicle.

EDUCATION:

Civil Engineering Bachelor degree Dec 2015

Lakehead University, Thunder Bay, ON

Civil Engineering Technologist (3-year Diploma) April 2010

Seneca College of Applied Arts & Technology

AutoCAD Civil 3D 2011 Certificate, Seneca College Dec 2010

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Project Coordinator/Engineer June 2016 – May 2018

BondField, Toronto, ON – Union Station Revitalization Project

- Review and process Shop Drawings, RFIs, CCNs, Change Orders, and other submittals.
- Communicate with sub trades and consulting engineers to solve on-site problems.
- Site inspections, special attention to structural elements (reinforcement, concrete, steel framing, etc).

Coop terms Project Coordinator – Construction Management

May 2014 - March 2016

EllisDon, Toronto, ON – Ryerson University SLC building

EllisDon, Toronto, ON – Residential Tower

EllisDon, Toronto, ON – Yorkdale Mall Expansion Project

- Assist the Project Manager with daily on-site and office activities.
- Issue RFI's, Site Instructions, Change Orders and revise newly issued drawings.
- Contacting subcontractors following up with tender documents and submissions.
- Site inspections, creating deficiency lists and reviews reports, making sure LEED standards are being followed on site.
- Creating an Environmental Protection Plan for the project.
- Tendering out contracts, comparing submitted bid packages.
- Studying Structural and Architectural drawings, requesting RFI's when necessary.

Page 2/2

Quality Assurance Inspector

Sept 2012 – July 2013

Aecon - Aecon Utility Engineering, Belleville, ON

(left to peruse Engineering degree)

- A site inspector for a solar energy farm. Constant site inspections, making sure the contractor is working up to quality and contract, proposing new methods and procedures to produce efficient and quality work.
- Analyze drawings, study contract documents, update site activity procedures, review quality checklists, and database management.

Site Inspector/Coordinator

Feb 2011-Jan 2012 (winter layoff)

Schaeffers Consulting Engineers, Vaughn, ON

- Made sure the contractor is working according to the contract drawings as well as municipal and regional standards.
- Coordinate between the contractor, the consulting engineers, and city and regional authorities.

Quality Control Technician

Aug 2010- Jan 2011 (winter layoff)

Golder Associates, Whitby, ON

- Conducted a variety of quality control tests on asphalt.
- Calculated and compared the results with ministry standards.
- Carried out general concrete lab duties.

Construction Quality Control

May 2009-Sept 2009 (Summer work period)

DAVROC, Brampton, ON

- Carried out general concrete lab duties.
- Conducted quality control tests and analysis on building materials using tools and equipment (concrete, asphalt, various types of soil).
- Completed daily material summaries.
- Inspected and monitored construction sites (buildings, roads).

Construction Labour

May 2007- Sept 2007

V.H.L. Development, Toronto, ON

- Worked as a general labour.
- Installed winter protection and water proofing and other safety measures.
- Operated various small equipment and machinery.

VOLUNTEER AND OTHER EXPERIENCES:

Swim Instructor and Lifequard

Present

City of Toronto, Parks and Recreation

- Certified Lifeguard, Swim and Emergency Fist Aid Instructor.
- Teach swimming to ages.
- Lifeguard and supervise the pool.

Armenian Community Center

Present

- Attend weekly meetings concerning organization within the center.
- Helped with organization and preparation for musical and social and fundraising events.

References Available Upon Request

Garo Arslanian (EIT)

| Project Name | Title | Project Description | Budget (\$ CAN) | Location | Employer |
|---|----------------------------------|---|--------------------|-------------------|---------------------------|
| Union Station Revitalization | Project Coordinator | Stages 2 & 3 of the renovation of Union Station's East wing, Bay Street promenade & concourse areas and heritage restoration works. | \$175 million | Toronto, ON | Bondfield Construction |
| Ryerson University SLC building (Yonge St. and Gould St.) | Project Coordinator (Coop) | 8 floors of multi-disciplinary building and a theater school. Unconventional Architectural/Structural design with extensive electrical, mechanical and Theatrical scopes. | multi- million | Toronto, ON | Ellis Don |
| Yorkdale Mall Expansion Project | Project Coordinator (Coop) | Comprised of five underground levels of parking and two levels of commercial steel construction. | 400+ Million | Toronto, ON | Ellis Don |
| Alto Residences Residential Building (Dundas St. and Dufferin St) | Project Coordinator (Coop) | Eight story high residential building, Silver LEED | multi- million | Toronto, ON | Ellis Don |
| Solar Energy Farm | Site Quality Assurance | 85ha of farm land converted to a solar energy generating farm. Panels placed on large tables and transformers to convert AC/DC power. | Unknown | Belleville, ON | Aecon |
| Residential Subdivision | Site Inspector | A golf course located in Brampton, was converted to housing subdivision with its underground services (sanitary, storm, water main), utilities, roads, houses and storm water management pond | Unknown | Brampton, ON | Schaeffers Engineers |







Solar Energy Park





Yorkdale Mall, Two level Commercial Units

Residential Subdivision, Underground Services